<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[mchck.org]]></title>
  <link href="http://mchck.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mchck.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-29T16:20:24+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://mchck.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Simon Schubert and the MC HCK project]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prototype kit funding succesful!]]></title>
    <link href="http://mchck.org/blog/2013-07-27-prototype_kit_funding_succesful/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-27T00:27:50+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mchck.org/blog/prototype_kit_funding_succesful</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><i>This text is an adapted version of what has been mailed to the
  prototype supporters.</i></p>
<p>Thanks to all supporters for ordering a MC HCK prototype kit and
  supporting the project!  The funding has been successful: almost all
  kits have been sold.</p>
<p>There are a few things that will help make the MC HCK a success:</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>First, please subscribe to the MC HCK mailinglist to follow the
  progress of the prototype order, and to exchange ideas and feedback
  for the MC HCK.  The mailing list is extremely low volume.  Go to
  <a href="https://0x2c.org/mailman/listinfo/nerds">https://0x2c.org/mailman/listinfo/nerds</a> to sign up.  Best do it now
  and then continue reading the email.</p>
<p>Second, if you bought a prototype kit, please make sure that you
  received a mail from me and that your shipping address mentioned in
  the mail is correct.</p>
<p>Third, a short status update;  unless something big happens, I will
  not email buyers with further updates.  Subscribe to the mailing list if
  you would like updates.</p>
<p>I have already received most parts for the kits, but some are on
  backorder.  The backorder is currently estimated to arrive on Sep 21,
  2013, but DigiKey&#8217;s estimation has been slipping.  I am thinking about
  getting these parts from a different distributor.</p>
<p>Thanks again to everybody for supporting the MC HCK project, and
  thanks for subscribing to the mailing list and contributing your
  ideas!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First parts for prototypes]]></title>
    <link href="http://mchck.org/blog/2013-07-19-First-parts-for-prototypes/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mchck.org/blog/First-parts-for-prototypes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everything is progressing smoothly with the prototypes!  We&#8217;ve sold
  40 prototype kits so far, which means that this undertaking will
  really happen.</p>
<p>Today, the first parts for the kits arrived:</p>
<p><img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5321/9318462017_2c2b164e6e_c_d.jpg" alt="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5321/9318462017_2c2b164e6e_c_d.jpg" /></p>
<!-- more -->
<p>DigiKey already shipped all parts that are not on backorder.  The
  stacks of LiPo batteries on the left, the bag of RF modules on the
  right, and the cute QFP48 programming adapters in front came from
  China using a TaoBao agent, which worked out nicely as well.</p>
<p>I realized that I forgot some Schottky diodes for running the LiPo
  batteries on USB input, and some ferrite beads for experiments in
  reducing ADC noise &#8211; I&#8217;ll add those to the outstanding DigiKey order.</p>
<p>The parts on backorder at DigiKey are:</p>
<ul>
  <li>the MCUs (already in their stock)</li>
  <li>reset/programming buttons (expected Aug 29)</li>
  <li>boost converters (first est. Sep 4, now expected Sep 15)</li>
</ul>
<p>What&#8217;s missing, besides antistatic + bubble bags (which are ordered),
  are the PCBs.  I have decided to open a patch window for now, given
  that we are waiting on parts anyways.  That means we can do some last
  changes to the design and layout, do a small prototype run using
  SeeedStudio or iTeadStudio, and still get the PCBs made in time.</p>
<p>If anybody has some not-too-intrusive suggestions for layout change,
  now would be the time to speak up.  Next opportunity will be after
  the prototype run when we collect experiences and feedback.</p>
<p>I have two changes I want to look into:</p>
<ul>
  <li>move the ferrite beads from the power input section to the analog
    supply lines of the MCU</li>
  <li>allow operation fro LiPo without Schottky diode</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prototypes Available]]></title>
    <link href="http://mchck.org/blog/2013-06-25-Prototypes-Available/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mchck.org/blog/Prototypes-Available</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to be able to announce the first prototype MC HCK dev
  kits.  These prototype kits are meant for early adopters, who would
  like to evaluate and verify the electrical design of the MC HCK, and
  those who want to contribute to the growing software library.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>During the past months of silence, several things have ripened to
  usefulness:</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve created a bootloader that allows firmware updates via USB; this
  means that the MC HCK can be programmed without additional programming
  adapters.  This also confirms that the MC HCK is definitely usable in
  its most basic form.</p>
<p>Additionally, using our custom SWD toolchain, it is possible to debug
  code on the MC HCK using gdb.  The toolchain currently supports the
  Bus Blaster and Bus Pirate boards as SWD adapters, but native
  MC HCK &lt;-&gt; MC HCK SWD debug support is underway.</p>
<p>The prototype kits will come in parts (not assembled) and will contain
  the following components:</p>
<ul>
  <li>5x MCU (pre-programmed with USB bootloader)</li>
  <li>5x boards (2.0 mm, direct USB pluggable)</li>
  <li>1x discretes for all parts</li>
  <li>2x NRF24L01+ RF board</li>
  <li>2x MCP73831T-2ACI LiPo charger IC</li>
  <li>2x 180mAh LiPo battery</li>
  <li>2x W25Q80BV 1MB SPI flash</li>
  <li>1x MIC5205-3.3 16V LDO</li>
  <li>1x LM3671MF-3.3 buck IC</li>
  <li>1x TPS61097-33 boost IC</li>
  <li>2x Micro-USB AB receptacles</li>
  <li>3x 32.768kHz RTC XTAL</li>
</ul>
<p>This allows you to build 5 standard MC HCKs, and run RF
  communications, autonomous nodes, log large amounts of data, and run
  from a variety of power sources.  Not all of these options have been
  verified to work yet, but that&#8217;s what this prototype kit is for.</p>
<p>The price of the prototype kit will be $60, and will include PayPal
  fee and international shipping, either from Switzerland or the
  European Union (your choice).  The total cost calculation can be found
  at <a href="https://github.com/mchck/mchck/wiki/Prototypes">Prototypes</a>.</p>
<p>To get to this price level, we need to purchase parts for 50 kits, and
  also sell 50 kits.</p>
<p>This is where we need your support:  We need 40 brave supporters, who
  will commit to buying each a prototype kit (ask your friends and
  hackspace!), and ideally transfer the money ahead of time.  Simon is personally
  prepared to eat the cost for up to 10 kits, should we not manage to
  find 50 buyers.</p>
<p>Due to IC factory lead times, we expect the kits to ship end of August.</p>
<p>You can directly commit to buying one prototype kit using the
  following links;  please leave your correct shipping information and
  email address, and make sure the receiving party ID is Simon, 2@0x2c.org.</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd%3D_xclick&amp;business%3DCCTESJYV55TTQ&amp;lc%3DCH&amp;item_name%3DMC%2BHCK%2Bprototype%2Bkit%2B(USD)&amp;amount%3D60.00&amp;currency_code%3DUSD&amp;button_subtype%3Dservices&amp;bn%3DPP-BuyNowBF:btn_buynowCC_LG.gif:NonHosted">$60, PayPal, USD</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd%3D_xclick&amp;business%3DCCTESJYV55TTQ&amp;lc%3DCH&amp;item_name%3DMC%2BHCK%2Bprototype%2Bkit%2B(EUR)&amp;amount%3D46.00&amp;currency_code%3DEUR&amp;button_subtype%3Dservices&amp;bn%3DPP-BuyNowBF:btn_buynowCC_LG.gif:NonHosted">€46, PayPal, EUR</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Or visit the Prototypes page at <a href="https://github.com/mchck/mchck/wiki/Prototypes">Prototypes</a> to ponder and commit.</p>
<p>If we don&#8217;t get to at least 40 kits within one month, we will refund
  all payments.</p>
<p>Thanks for your continued interest and support!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
